

Francesco Fucci

Lead Software Engineer

August 3, 1987

Benoitstraat 17, 5654BT Eindhoven

+31 6 25 35 53 30

§ fr.fucci

@ fr.fucci@hotmail.it

EU Citizenship

Social Network



Github Page

LinkedIn Page

Languages

Italian

English

French

Programming

- \rightarrow C++ (11/14/17)
- » Julia
- » C
- » Python

Learning

- » Rust
- » Haskell

Working Experience

2021 - now

Lead Software Engineer

ASML

Experience in leading team of 4-6 people. Prepare design documents, define tasks that team member can execute, perform code-reviews and design reviews. I write code with the team, while supervising that they can achieve deadlines. Contributed to different deliverables: the design of different of a library for tensor-based operations (i.e. einsum) using template-meta programming, algorithms for value interpolation.

2019 - 2021 Software Design Engineer

ASML

- Development of calibration application for NXE machines (Python/C++)
- Development of a quadratic programming interior point solver in **Julia** and in **C++**.
- Refactoring of legacy C++ components to newer standards.
 Definition of the architecture of software components for new ASML machines, using C++ 11. Analyzed code performance with statistical benchmarks (i.e., Google Microbenchmark)

2015 - 2019 Senior Software Engineer

Critiware

- Contributed to the design of the plasma control system, which will be the control software system responsible of controlling part of the plant systems of the ITER Machine (https://www.iter.org). Design of the system using Model-Driven Design approaches from requirements analysis to structural solution. Contributed to the implementation of real-time software prototype in (C++14) on Linux RHEL 6.
- Development of tools to assess the tolerance to software errors, which is now used in production to assess Android OS low-level code using (C++11).
- Tools for the analysis of post-drive run for trains (Java, Eclipse RCP Dependency Injection Framework).
- Developed a DSL to aid developers to assess Python code.

2011 – 2012 Software Engineer

SESI

Toolchain tailoring automatic code generation of test code for ATC applications.

Education

Postgraduate Training

2013 – 2014 PhD Research Internship

EDEI

I contributed on the development of components for a platform for the automated analysis of systems code. I developed an interpreter in C++, which executes symbolic expressions. The project is available at the following address: S2E

Francesco Fucci

Lead Software Engineer

About Me -

I enjoy building systems and learning new things. Currently my favorite study topics are modern programming languages, highperformance system design, quantitative methods and machine learning. I worked in several domains from railways systems, fusion, and lithography machines.

Design Skills -

- Agile Software Design: SOLID, Design Patterns
- >> Numerical Optimization
- Machine Learning
- Deep-Learning
- Operating Systems
- Systems Design

Other Skills

- **MATLAB**
- Git
- Jenkins
- Boost
- Tensoflow
- Keras

Keywords

Agile

Team-oriented

Collaboration Goal-oriented

Quick-learning

ΑI

Academic

2012 - 2015PhD Computer Engineering

> Thesis: Model-based verification of Operating Systems device drivers. In my thesis I explored different techniques for automatic verification of device drivers like runtime verification and symbolic execution.

Certificates

Coursera

Prowareness

Deep Learning Specialization Scrum Foundation

Agile Academy

Personal Projects

M-Opt A C + +20 framework to price options with Montecarlo method

(ongoing project). link

SLANG A DSL to specify contracts for device driver verification (C++, Boost,

Java).

Selected Publications

2019 Management of the ITER PCS design using a system- engi-

neering approach

F.Fucci et Al.

28th IEEE Symposium on Fusion Engineering (SOFE)

2016 Software Aging Analysis of the Android Mobile OS

> D. Cotroneo, F. Fucci, A. K. Iannillo, R. Natella, R. Pietrantuono. IEEE International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering

2015 MoIO: Run-Time Monitoring for I/O Protocol Violations in

Storage Device Drivers;

D. Cotroneo, L. De Simone, F. Fucci, R. Natella.

IEEE International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering

2013 SABRINE: StAte-Based Robustness testIng of operatiNg

D. Cotroneo, D. Di Leo, F. Fucci, R. Natella

IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engi-

neering (ASE)

Awards

2012 Best Paper Award

Best Paper Award 5th International Conference on Dependability

(DEPEND)

2006-2007 Best Student Award

Best student of the of University of Napoli "Federico II" Computer

Engineering faculty.